[engine starts]
[Jerry] This is a 1963
VW Karmann Ghia in sea blue.
It happens to be equipped
with a 4-cylinder,
Porsche 912 engine, suspension and brakes.
But that is a secret.
This was a sports car for guys
that wanted a sports car,
but also wanted a VW.
So, you had to have a sense of humor.
I love it.
[phone ringing]
This is Joel.
[Jerry] Joel, what's up?
-Jerry, what's happening?
-Nothing.
[Joel] Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
[Jerry] Yes.
Hi, I'm Jerry Seinfeld,
and this is Comedians
in Cars Getting Coffee.
[Jerry] Today my guest is Joel Hodgson,
creator of Mystery Science Theater 3000,
and one of my favorite
cultural visionaries.
[Joel] You know, I knew you
when you only had one car.
That's how long I've known you.
[Jerry] There's Hernandez
Sewer Cleaning & Heating.
For all your cleaning needs.
[Jerry] Video inspection of sewer lines.
Well, there's a movie I want to see.
"Honey, run that video of our sewer line
one more time."
"What's on cable tonight?"
"Uh, not too much. We got
the video inspection of sewer lines."
[Jerry] "Let's watch that.
And then, show my colonic inspection.
What's that called?"
-[coughs]
-[both laughing]
How do we both go to that, right?
So quickly.
[Jerry] Do you remember
somebody wrote a piece,
and they described you as the adult result
of an overstimulated childhood?
-Do you remember that?
-No, I don't remember.
[Jerry] You took every product
they put out there,
every cereal, right to the soul.
A guy who thought Kellogg's and Mattel
had a master plan that couldn't fail.
And, no, not in the least.
They were not thinking about me at all.
[cyclist talks indistinctly]
You got it.
-Oh, [bleep] you.
-[Jerry] Oh.
I know, I think he wants to ride with us.
He does. Crack your window.
-[cyclist] I thought that was you...
-[Jerry] I like that bike.
[cyclist] I got something for you.
I don't want it.
[cyclist laughs]
Wow! You look good, man.
So do you. You've really kept it up.
Now, is this the kind of car
that you'd really worry about
if I were to wreck it?
Like, you would get upset, right?
Who's not upset when they wreck a car?
[Joel] I guess you're right.
[Jerry] Welcome to North New Jersey,
embroidery capital of the world.
I know, I always felt
that should be embroidered.
Like, if they're so great,
-show me something big.
-Yeah.
[Jerry] Look at that dump truck.
Now, that's a great vehicle.
That's a thing that's just made
to be shrunken down,
so you can get it in your hand.
People love to re-purpose a phrase.
I mean, "dump truck"
is just sitting there waiting
for some new type of elimination process
to be branded.
We're calling it "the dump truck."
[laughing]
And then they look at you, "Good, huh?"
[Jerry] Look at how people drive now.
See, improvements in the engineering
of cars has enabled people
to express their inner [bleep] hole-ness.
You think, "Why are people
so ill behaved?" They're not.
They just never had the tools
to express it before.
So technology is making us
bigger [bleep] heads than ever.
That's right.
[Jerry] What do you think of the Cube?
Um, I like it.
[Jerry] I think it's, like,
people that want to be driving something,
so when the robots take over,
they won't be mad at them.
-Yeah.
-"I'm one of you."
"Let him pass, he's driving the Cube."
Mad Men is so great still.
-Yeah, I love it.
-I'm still in the middle of it.
I'm watching it.
We were on to that in the '80s.
That's all we wanted,
was to be advertising guys in the '60s.
That's right.
-We used to talk about that all the time.
-All the time.
-Drinking at lunch...
-Yep.
-...and having a bar in your office.
Is that a shared dream
of all guys our age?
Of course it is.
And the sexual revolution
was all tied up in that.
Yep.
I mean,
that's what the sports cars were about.
Women will give this to you,
if you have the right accessories.
Hey, there's a fantastic spot
right up front.
How could I say no to that?
Remember when we were kids,
you'd see cars,
every one looked so different.
Each car looked so different.
So unique unto itself.
This whole...
This is just oatmeal.
Yeah, they're grinding
all the edges off, Jerry.
-Just the same thing they're doing to us.
-There's your Saab.
[Jerry chuckles]
-I would love coffee.
-I'll take a coffee, too.
[Jerry] This place is weird.
Most things that are weird
are not weird good.
-And this is weird good.
-This is weird good.
[Jerry] It's another '50s diner.
Why are we looking back all the time?
This diner is about
looking backward, right?
So, why are we looking back?
Because when you look back,
you know what you're gonna say.
That's why.
-Right.
-You know what to say about the past.
But you don't know
what to say about the future.
-Damn it, you're smart.
-See?
The economics of a restaurant are always
beyond my mental comprehension.
So, I come and I get
a tuna sandwich for $4.50,
and that enables you
to run this whole place?
That's why so many restaurants
don't make it.
So many people think they have
a good idea for a restaurant.
And the guy that makes all the money
is the guy who sells the equipment.
Just like the guy who sells the guitars
makes the money.
-He does?
-And not the guy in the band.
How many guitars have you bought
over the years?
-Two or three.
-Yeah, see?
Do you play the guitar?
-No.
-Yeah.
You know how many I've bought?
Six. And I don't play the guitar.
But the other thing
that's an object of fascination
that I've found of comedians of all kinds,
and this goes back to the Mad Men thing,
the corporate environment.
The idea of bosses and employees
is just hilarious to us.
Why is that so funny?
-Well, we don't have to do it, right?
-[laughing]
It's such a typically human attempt
to organize what is un-organizable.
-Right?
-You're right.
We just see the hopelessness of trying
to organize human endeavor
into a building.
We'd like to be in a system...
That works.
If you can agree
with me that I'm your boss,
and you do what I say,
everything is gonna be fine.
What do you think of this ketchup
with the cap on the bottom?
It's great.
How many fights did they have over this
before someone said,
"But the ketchup goes to the bottom.
Put the cap on the bottom."
What about the passing-gas sound problem
of the ketchup?
Do you think they talk about that?
You know...
[squirts]
"Hey, how's that upside-down jar
coming along?"
-"It's fantastic, people love it."
-"Focus groups, off the charts."
"We do have one problem."
"What could possibly be the problem?"
"When the bottle's been
sitting upright..."
"Mm-hmm. I'm with you.
It's filled with our good ketchup.
Go ahead."
"Well, sir, it's not something
we've ever faced before
in our ketchup bottles."
"My wife's picking me up in 15 minutes.
Could you get to the point?"
He's gotta be in a tux.
Him and his wife are going to a function.
Yeah, he's putting on his cuff links,
he's doing his tie.
Looking at the opera tickets.
"It's this, sir."
"Sounds normal to me.
Sounds like our new upside-down bottle
extruding our good ketchup."
[sighs]
"Well, what do you propose we do?
There is a chance that the consumer
will not find it objectionable,
and it'll be kind of like
the slowness of our older bottle."
-"Or?"
-"Or we potentially have a PR problem.
Frankly, we're worried about these
YouTube kids getting a hold of this."
"They could have a field day with this,
if you know what I mean."
"Anderson here feels
if we can get out in front of this thing
and make fun of it ourselves,
then we would be perceived
as in on the joke."
"Roll the 'Who let one?' reel.
This is just a test reel,
but this shows you some
of the funny things we can do with this.
If we get the okay from you, that is."
[laughing]
What are you laughing about?
Why are movies so much more fun
to make fun of than television?
They're aspiring
to present God's point of view.
It's big.
This is life in all its fury.
-Yes.
-You know?
[Jerry] Did you like Avatar?
I did. I bought the entire dream.
My favorite part was that guy
in the helicopter with the coffee cup.
When they were attacking. Remember him?
That was part of his breakfast,
killing people.
Part of his complete breakfast.
-Right. Big mug of joe.
-"I just need something.
Why aren't I waking up? Oh, that's right.
I've gotta give someone a taste
of hell from on high."
"Fill these natives full of lead.
That's how I start my day."
"That's a bracer."
Uhh. Mmm!
"Now, I'm up."
"If I haven't killed,
I'm just no good in the morning.
"You gonna wanna kill that guy?
Because I could go
for another one right now."
[both laughing]